Guide to the Paper Tiger Television Records MSS.276
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VII. Video Productions, 1980-2014; 131.4 Linear Feet in 110 record cartons, 11 cassette boxes, 10 upright video containers, and 2 LP boxes.; 1000 U-matic; 339 MiniDV; 199 VHS; 108 Hi8; 46 Betacam_SP; 16 1_Inch_Video_Reel; 7 S-VHS; 4 Digital_Betacam; 2 DVCAM; 1 Betacam; 1 audiocassette; 2.06
  - Subseries VII.B: Non-Broadcast Videos, 1980-2014
    - Olof Palme Memorial Lecture, undated (Box 125, U-matic 276_1035)
    - Omni Show, undated
      - Edited master -- Intro (Box 71, U-matic 276_0266)
      - Joan's Omni Show (Box 71, U-matic 276_0267)
    - One Family -- Global Action Project, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0468)
    - Open, Close, undated (Box 147, U-matic 276_0976)
    - Open to the Public, undated (Box 182, Minidv 276_1220)
    - Opening, undated (Box 182, Minidv 276_1239)
    - Opening Credits -- Rap Music, Camcorder Theme, undated (Box 134, U-matic 276_1145)
    - Opening for WPTP, undated (Box 183, Minidv 276_1241)
    - Our trip, roll 1, undated (Box 103, U-matic 276_0531)
    - Palestine Contingent Demonstration, undated (Box 185, Minidv 276_1396)
    - Paper Tiger TV in Austin, Texas -- Tape #1, undated (Box 71, U-matic 276_0259)
    - Papo Colo and Luis Fracia, New School, undated
      - U-matic recording (Box 123, U-matic 276_0739)
      - Hi8 recording (Box 181, Hi8 276_1065)
    - Peace March B-Roll, 59th Street, undated (Box 186, Minidv 276_1442)
    - Pela Trilha De Arquimedes, undated (Box 84, Vhs 276_0496)
    - People rally, march and interviews in Ann Arbor, Michigan, undated (Box 129, U-matic 276_0877)
      Transfer from VHS
    - Pirate Radio -- Experimental rough cut, undated (Box 152, U-matic 276_1651)
    - Playback #324, undated (Box 182, Minidv 276_1191)
    - Poema: Tata Te Ve o TV, by Cecilia Guidos, undated (Box 113, U-matic 276_0690)
    - Police State, undated
      - Part one (Box 189, Minidv 276_1015)
      - Part two (Box 189, Minidv 276_1001)
    - Portland Girl Convention, undated (Box 116, Vhs 276_0788)
    - Postal Interview #1, undated (Box 185, Minidv 276_1400)
    - Powell, undated (Box 150, Vhs 276_1624)
    - Press Conference, NBC Act 3, undated (Box 186, Hi8 276_1492)
    - PTTV German, undated (Box 116, Vhs 276_0731)
    - Public Access Demo, undated
      - Ilona's Cam, May 2 (Box 72, U-matic 276_0287)
      - U-matic recording (Box 74, U-matic 276_0310)
    - Public Enemy -- 24 minute cut, undated (Box 186, Minidv 276_1448)
    - Puffin Room Labor Demonstration, undated
      - Tape one (Box 184, Hi8 276_1389)
      - Tape two (Box 185, Hi8 276_1390)
    - Radio and Map -- Master, undated (Box 153, U-matic 276_1658)
    - Rage in Harlem, Paper Tiger Count and Open, undated (Box 80, Betacam sp 276_0400)
    - Rally in San Diego / Kevin Hever, Marine, undated (Box 137, U-matic 276_1790)
    - Rap Kids, Media Show, undated (Box 180, Hi8 276_0763)
    - Rap Kids, News World Order -- Master dub, undated (Box 126, U-matic 276_1082)
    - Rapping footage -- Tape two, undated (Box 105, U-matic 276_0563)
    - Reilel Hadi, undated (Box 123, U-matic 276_0869)
    - Rev. Billy, Jay's Photos, Meredith, Susan Howard, undated (Box 145, U-matic 276_0951)
    - Richard Green -- Crown Heights Youth Collective Crime Show, undated (Box 188, Hi8 276_1570)
    - Riverfront and May Day Fest, undated (Box 82, Hi8 276_0445)
    - RNC 8 Vlog, undated
      - Part one (Box 186, Minidv 276_1441)
      - Part two (Box 184, Minidv 276_1297)
    - Roar of the Fire Korean Anti-War Documentary, undated (Box 185, Minidv 276_1394)
    - Roll-Ins, Berlin Demonstration, ROMA Segment, undated (Box 153, U-matic 276_1656)
    - Rough Cut, undated (Box 186, Minidv 276_1506)
    - Rough Open, DeeDee, undated (Box 137, U-matic 276_1787)
    - RTS Garden Demonstration Footage, undated (Box 148, U-matic 276_0994)
    - RTTC, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1539)
    - San Paolo, tape 1, undated (Box 122, U-matic 276_0861)
    - Scene extra, 3 scumcam, undated (Box 188, Hi8 276_1567)
    - Schuller, Barnes and Noble, undated (Box 188, Hi8 276_1569)
    - Sean Gervasi, undated (Box 151, U-matic 276_1643)
    - Seattle Central Community College Panel Discussion -- The Middle East, Caryn Cline, undated (Box 121, Vhs 276_0852)
    - Seattle, WA, undated (Box 135, U-matic 276_1158)
    - Seattle WA Teach In / Seattle Coalition, undated (Box 135, U-matic 276_1155)
    - Shatilla #109, 2-14, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1543)
    - Shoot at Chinese staff and workers screening, undated (Box 188, Hi8 276_1566)
    - Shots in Bus, Welcome to Al Anwar, undated (Box 147, U-matic 276_0980)
    - Simin orientates, undated (Box 179, Hi8 276_0711)
    - Sin Sin Naughty / WKRP in Cincinnati, undated (Box 81, U-matic 276_0412)
    - Skip Blumberg, City Streets, undated (Box 116, Vhs 276_0791)
    - Solni -- 3 Min, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1559)
    - Somalia Demonstration, undated
      - U-matic recording (Box 141, U-matic 276_1381)
      - U-matic recording (Box 141, U-matic 276_1382)
    - South Brooklyn Community High School Cycle 2, undated (Box 150, Vhs 276_1623)
    - South Brooklyn March, undated (Box 181, Hi8 276_1055)
    - Spaulding CT / Bug Eye, undated (Box 184, Minidv 276_1320)
    - The Spectrum Spectacular, undated (Box 184, Minidv 276_1296)
    - "The State of Iraq" Panel, undated
      - Part one (Box 189, Minidv 276_1012)
      - Part two (Box 189, Minidv 276_1022)
    - Stella Demonstration, undated
      - U-matic recording (Box 150, U-matic 276_1617)
      - B-roll (Box 150, U-matic 276_1616)
    - Street, undated (Box 186, Hi8 276_1501)
    - Street Interviews, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1556)
    - Street Interviews for FIB, Coney Island, undated (Box 185, Minidv 276_1425)
    - Student Rally and March on Wall Street, undated
      - Laura Hibber (Box 118, U-matic 276_0814)
      - U-matic recording (Box 118, U-matic 276_0813)
    - Subway Movie -- Brock Peters, et al., Molly channels title, undated (Box 78, U-matic 276_0372)
    - Subways, undated
      - Day one, #1 (Box 140, U-matic 276_1368)
      - Day two, #3 (Box 140, U-matic 276_1367)
    - Sue Lott / Sue Boggs / Detroit, undated (Box 134, U-matic 276_1151)
    - Super Power: the Movie, undated (Box 182, Minidv 276_1195)
    - The Supernaturals -- Part one dub, undated (Box 77, U-matic 276_0353)
    - Susan R. Jott's tape, undated (Box 116, Vhs 276_0793)
    - SWOP (Southwest Organizing Project) and Las Vegas Strike -- Edit without titles, undated (Box 72, U-matic 276_0275)
    - Taiwan Footage, undated (Box 124, U-matic 276_0744)
      Dub from JVHS
    - Tammy, B-Roll, Jenn Aitken, undated (Box 184, Minidv 276_1302)
    - Tape with Bars, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1534)
    - Teaching Immigrants and Immigration, undated
      - Tape one (Box 189, Minidv 276_1598)
      - Tape two (Box 189, Minidv 276_1599)
    - Tetsuo Kogawa in San Francisco -- Interview and Presentation, undated
      - Part one (Box 152, U-matic 276_1654)
      - Part two (Box 152, U-matic 276_1653)
    - Thanksgiving Eve Anti-Intervention Demonstration, undated
      - Part one dub (Box 120, U-matic 276_0837)
      - Part two (Box 122, U-matic 276_0859)
    - Think Progressive Interview, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1550)
    - Tiger Countdown, Old Opener -- Master, undated (Box 147, U-matic 276_0977)
    - Tijuana demo, undated (Box 117, U-matic 276_0804)
    - Time in Next Week -- Address Poet, undated (Box 147, U-matic 276_0973)
    - Time Warner Demo, undated
      Shot by Martha Wallner on Hi-8
      - #1 -- Preparing props for demo at Avenue D (Box 72, U-matic 276_0285)
      - #2 (Box 72, U-matic 276_0286)
    - Topeka Peace Coalition Tag "Strength Thru Patience", undated (Box 111, U-matic 276_0638)
    - TPTV Compilation, a Global Action Production, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0458)
    - Trempealeau Community TV, Nowak Rally, Minneapolis Community TV, undated (Box 108, U-matic 276_0597)
    - The Trickle Down Theory of Sorrow, Part 1: Safe at Home, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0467)
    - TV Pinel, undated (Box 84, Vhs 276_0502)
    - TV Sala de Espera, Brasil -- Sampler shot about cooperatives in the town for cheaper food, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0488)
    - TV Viva, Brazil, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0460)
    - Twin Towers, Karina Correa, undated (Box 185, Minidv 276_1397)
    - UDC, Giovanni Interview, undated (Box 186, Hi8 276_1504)
    - UMWA Yugoslav Tape #3 -- Interview with Bill Weinberg, undated (Box 151, U-matic 276_1639)
    - UN Demo -- Chris Hoover with Interviews -- Dub master, undated (Box 165, U-matic 276_1802)
    - Union Square Shots, Armory Shots, undated (Box 185, Minidv 276_1434)
    - University of Amherst -- Original submaster edit, undated (Box 135, U-matic 276_1153)
    - Vagrom -- Tape 1, undated (Box 84, Vhs 276_0516)
    - Video Press Sample, Tokyo, Japan, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0493)
    - Video WKOP, Mik Flow, undated (Box 181, Minidv 276_1177)
    - Viet combat vet -- Military Families Support Network, undated (Box 119, U-matic 276_0827)
    - Views on the War interviews with Brookline High School, undated (Box 126, Vhs 276_1084)
    - Waiting Room TV, Brazil, undated (Box 83, Vhs 276_0491)
    - War Resisters League, undated
      - Marine Reservists -- Dub (Box 136, U-matic 276_1166)
      - Hi8 recording (Box 180, Hi8 276_0857)
      - U-matic recording (Box 109, U-matic 276_0618)
    - Washington DC, logged by Kelly -- Master dub, undated (Box 119, U-matic 276_0818)
    - Without Television / Yutaka Tsuchiya, undated
      - Office -- Master (Box 83, Vhs 276_0472)
      - Master (Box 83, Vhs 276_0473)
    - Women Speak Out, Iowa landscapes, undated (Box 131, U-matic 276_0894)
    - Woodstock Anti-War Rally, undated
      - Songs and poetry (Box 137, U-matic 276_1788)
      - U-matic recording (Box 137, U-matic 276_1789)
    - WPTP, undated
      - #5 (Box 151, Vhs 276_1634)
      - Kim Moody (Box 185, Minidv 276_1424)
    - Y2K Interviews, undated
      - Jim Fadden -- Master (Box 115, Vhs 276_0719)
      - Phyllis, Joe, Lola (Box 116, Vhs 276_0720)
    - Youth 92 -- Edited master, undated (Box 71, U-matic 276_0264)
    - Youth Market, undated (Box 187, Minidv 276_1538)
    - Yugo Selects, undated
      - U-matic recording (Box 152, U-matic 276_1650)
      - U-matic recording (Box 152, U-matic 276_1649)
- Series VIII. Objects, 1982-2002; 7.6 Linear Feet in 15 flat boxes.
  Series VIII. Objects (1982-2002) contains items used in production such as props, banners, clothing, "crankees" (hand-painted scrolls used to display credits in videos), and backdrops.
  - Subseries VIII.A: Props, undated
    Series VIII.A Props (undated) contains props used in Paper Tiger TV's television production, such as constructed objects, clothing, buttons, and banners.
    Series VIII.A Props (undated) is arranged alphabetically.
    - Banner with political buttons, Undated (Box 40, Object ID: 276.2.0001)
    - Denim jacket with crankee on the back, Undated (Box 42, Object ID: 276.2.0002)
    - Felt cloth with tigers, Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0016)
    - Framed National Geographic cover - painted, Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0003)
    - Framed photograph of Herb Schiller with wire on glass, Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0004)
    - Grey "TV" box - large, Undated (Object ID: 276.2.0005)
    - Grey "TV" box - small, Undated (Object ID: 276.2.0006)
    - Large wooden prop TV remote control - blue, Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0007)
    - Large wooden prop TV remote control - pink, Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0008)
    - Operation Storm the Media - camcorder commando vests (2), Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0015)
    - Paper Tiger TV logo - in black picture frame, Undated (Box 40, Object ID: 276.2.0009)
    - Plastic hook hand, Undated (Box 41, Object ID: 276.2.0010)
    - Political buttons, Undated (Box 40, Object ID: 276.2.0011)
    - Shrinky-dink pins, earrings, and magnets, Undated (Box 40, Object ID: 276.2.0012)
    - Tiger stripe box (red and black) with slit cut in lid, Undated (Object ID: 276.2.0013)
    - Toy phone - yellow plastic, Undated (Box 40, Object ID: 276.2.0014)
  - Subseries VIII.B: Crankees, 1982-1992
    Series VIII.B Crankees (1982-1992) contains Crankees, or hand-painted scrolls used to display credits in Paper Tiger videos.
    Series VIII.B Crankees (1982-1992) is arranged first by show number, and then alphabetically.
    - Show # 13, 1982 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0044, Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0070)
    - Show # 15, 1982 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0030)
    - Show # 18, 1982 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0034)
    - Show # 22, 1983 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0074)
    - Show # 23, 1982 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0075)
    - Show # 27, 1983 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0029)
    - Show # 30, 1983 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0049)
    - Show # 33, 1982 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0031)
    - Show # 38, 1983 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0032)
    - Show # 40, 1983 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0071)
    - Show # 41, 1983 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0047)
    - Show # 42, 1983 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0033)
    - Show # 43, 1983 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0041)
    - Show # 56, 1984 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0039)
    - Show # 57, 1984 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0035)
    - Show # 58, 1984 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0023)
    - Show # 65, 1985 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0045)
    - Show # 70, 1985 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0048, Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0073)
    - Show # 74, 1985 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0065, ID: 276.2.0072)
    - Show # 79, 1985 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0042, ID: 276.2.0046)
    - Show # 80, 1985 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0050)
    - Show # 96, 1986 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0051)
    - Show # 102, 1986 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0020, Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0068)
    - Show # 113, 1987 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0024, ID: 276.2.0027)
    - Show # 119, 1987 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0019)
    - Show # 120, 1987 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0060, ID: 276.2.0081)
    - Show # 121, 1987 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0021, Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0040, Object: ID: 276.2.0043)
    - Show # 137, 1987 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0022)
    - Show # 140, 1988 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0079)
    - Show # 172, 1990 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0026)
    - Show # 180, 1990 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0025)
    - Show # 185, 1990 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0018)
    - Show # 186, 1990 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0028)
    - Show # 191, 1990 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0038, Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0056)
    - Show # 193, 1990 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0063)
    - Show # 195, 1991 (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0037)
    - Show # 196 / 197, 1991 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0053, ID: 276.2.0076, ID: 276.2.0080)
    - Show # 199, 1991 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0061, ID: 276.2.0062, ID: 276.2.0077)
    - Show # 214, 1991 (Box 43, Object ID: 276.2.0017)
    - Show # 226, 1992 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0054)
    - [? Reads Between the Lines] - horizontal, Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0066)
    - College Students Reading College Newspapers (workshop), Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0067)
    - Deep Dish TV intro "Coming Soon", 1986 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0057)
    - "If You Like This Show..." general, Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0058)
    - Inflated Budget - unknown show, Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0064)
    - NYSCA Budget Cuts protest, Undated (Box 44, Object ID: 276.2.0036)
    - Paper Tiger TV Manifesto, Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0052, ID: 276.2.0069)
    - Unknown show with musicians / bands, Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0059)
    - Wexner Center Installation piece (with list of members), 1991 (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0078)
    - Working / Factory / Alienation - horizontal (unknown show / event), Undated (Box 45, Object ID: 276.2.0055)
  - Subseries VIII.C: Backdrops and Banners, 1991-2002
    Series VIII.C Backdrops and Banners (1991-2002) contains backdrops and banners used in Paper Tiger TV productions.
    Series VIII.C Backdrops and Banners (1991-2002) is arranged alphabetically.
    - Access for All, Undated (Box 47, Object ID: 276.2.0094)
    - Access Orbit - signed by kids who worked on production, c. 2002 (Box 47, Object ID: 276.2.0107)
    - Admit One ticket, Undated (Box 47, Object ID: 276.2.0087)
    - "Attention: The Corporate Media Lied to You" from Freeing the Media conference, 1999 (Box 47, Object ID: 276.2.0111)
    - Bush, Undated (Box 47, Object ID: 276.2.0089)
    - "The Church Must Be Altared", Undated (Box 48, Object ID: 276.2.0086)
    - Classroom - [Pedagogy of Television], Undated (Box 48, Object ID: 276.2.0085)
    - Disney Times Square - from show # 273, 1998 (Box 48, Object ID: 276.2.0104)
    - Evict Guiliani - NYC Quality of Life, Undated (Box 48, Object ID: 276.2.0092)
    - Free the Media - From March to the Moguls (tiger with camera), Undated (Box 48, Object ID: 276.2.0097)
    - "Freeing the Media" from Freeing the Media conference, 1999 (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0112)
    - Green Circus, Undated (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0091)
    - Information Libre, Undated (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0093)
    - "It's Corporate, Not Public", Undated (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0095)
    - Landscape with billboards - made for Wexner Center, Undated (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0083)
    - Landscape with tree and satellite dishes - made for Wexner Center, Undated (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0082)
    - Landscape with Yellow Brick Road, Undated (Box 49, Object ID: 276.2.0106)
    - Le Tigre Cafe - from show # 263B, 1994 (Box 50, Object ID: 276.2.0096)
    - Map of America, Undated (Box 50, Object ID: 276.2.0098)
    - March Against the Media Moguls, Undated (Box 50, Object ID: 276.2.0108)
    - March Against the Media Moguls - hung on bus, 1991 (Box 50, Object ID: 276.2.0110)
    - News Boy and Girl - with tigers, Undated (Box 50, Object ID: 276.2.0105)
    - "PTTV Smashing the Myths", Undated (Box 51, Object ID: 276.2.0100)
    - Side of Building with flower pots, Undated (Box 51, Object ID: 276.2.0103)
    - Solidarity, Undated (Box 51, Object ID: 276.2.0090)
    - Suburban Driveway, Undated (Box 51, Object ID: 276.2.0101)
    - Subway Car - [German], Undated (Box 51, Object ID: 276.2.0099)
    - Subway Car - Post Herb Schiller (with a lot of graffiti), Undated (Box 51, Object ID: 276.2.0102)
    - Tree, Undated (Box 52, Object ID: 276.2.0109)
    - TV Control Room - made for Whitney exhibit, used for several shows, Undated (Box 52, Object ID: 276.2.0084)
    - Voting Booth, Undated (Box 52, Object ID: 276.2.0088)
- Series IX. Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 4 websites in 4 archived websites.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued annually.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://papertiger.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567. Videos are inconsistently captured.
  Paper Tiger Television's website was first collected in 2007, documenting the organization's 25th anniversary. From 2009-2015, the website was captured more consistently, and contains information on their many projects and video series, such as the Paper Tiger Reads Working Women, Surveilling Surveillance, Urban Environmentalism: DIY Living Green, Gentrification in Sunset Park, Military Myths, production on the Peace Pentagon, Public Spaces, Exposing Deception, social movements, Detroit, fast food workers strike, and El Taller Latino Americano. The website also contained information with descriptions of their historical programs and information on their weekly Wednesday broadcasts. Their blog contained descriptions of their programs, dating back to 2007 as well as events listings and some behind the scenes information. Video topics included art, community gardens, democracy and dissent, DIY and grassroots media, feminism, education, environment, events, free speech and censorship, science and technology, globalization, health, immigration, labor, LGTBQIA+, media criticism, peace and conflict, politics, pop culture, public space, race and class, science and technology, social movements, urban politics, women, consumerism and capitalism, and youth. In circa 2016-2017, the website redesigned to highlight the Paper Tiger archives (both images and video) and their more recent work dating until 2021. They also were a frequent collaborator with Deep Dish Television, on projects related to Mumia Abu-Jamal and organizing against "white nationalism, neoliberalism, patriarchy, and colonialism" after the election of President Donald Trump.